ANJALI RAMCHANDANI

anjaliramchandani21@gmail.com | (951)563-7421 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/anjaliramchandani

Summary

Generalist Software Engineer with 4+ yrs. of experience in C/C++, Go. Diverse skills in system software and backend development. Proven abilities in software integration, research, software architecture design and code optimization. Follows Agile Methodology for project delivery. Resourceful, creative, team oriented and passionate to engage in different technologies.

Technical Skills

LANGUAGES & PROTOCOLS: C, C++, JavaScript, Go, Java, LIBRARIES / FRAMEWORKS: Express.js, Hadoop, Kafka, REST.

Python, GraphQL, HTML/CSS, SQL, TCP/IP, Websockets.

TOOLS AND PLATFORMS: Git, AWS, POSIX threads, Bash, FreeRTOS.

Relevant Experience

PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT INTERN

ZTech | Austin, TX, United States

(June 2020 - Aug 2020)

- Reelable: Leveraged knowledge in Git, API design for developing robust server-side code (with Express.js and GraphQL).
- Consolidated feature requirements from team and developed system architecture design.
- ZTech Chat: Developed microservices based backend with Node.js, AWS lambda and PostgreSQL based database.
- Led engineering team in development of chat solution, customer database, onboarding pages, lead generation for the MVP

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Intrepid Control Systems | Pune, MH, India

(July 2017 – June 2019)

- neoOBD2SDK (github.com/intrepidcs/neoobd2_sdk): Built open source C SDK for vehicle network tools to connect to IoT apps.
- Leveraged knowledge in Git and Markdown to introduce the global team to better code and documentation standards.
- Utilized FreeRTOS and its tasks based multi-threading to implement MQTT applications.
- Independently developed end-to-end application demos with AWS IoT, and other AWS services.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Alba Consulting | Pune, MH, India

(Oct 2016 – July 2017)

- Project Bioscope (IP-CCTV surveillance): Developed REST API over websockets for IP-CCTV surveillance application.
- Implemented stream collectors for distributed Kafka based application in **Go**.
- Implemented stream conversions from RTP to HLS with C++ (C++11), FFMPEG and Bash scripts.
- Leverage knowledge in protocol buffers and gRPC for marshalling and inter-process communication.
- Alba Lock: Developed firmware and optimized code to align with object-oriented principles in low-level language such as C.
- Supervised a team of two for the design and implementation of SCP based protocol with AES encryption.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Palette Tech | Pune, MH, India

(Sep 2015-Sep 2016)

- Home Automation System: Independently built firmware for Zigbee devices by reverse-engineering TI ZStack.
- Developed custom communication logic between Linux gateway and Android app using TCP/IP socket programming.

Relevant Projects:

DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEMS COURSE

@UC Riverside

(July 2020 - Aug 2020)

- ShopDB: Generated ER diagram and Relational schema for complex DBs and adding optimizations with domains and regex.
- Implementing the SQL queries for PostgreSQL DB in Java with error handling and using PostgreSQL API to resolve errors in PKs.

DEEP LEARNING COURSE

@UC Riverside

(Mar 2020 - June 2020)

- Traffic Signal Control Using Reinforcement Learning Agents: Implemented and compared two different methods of RL, i.e. Deep Q learning and A2C. Utilized Tensorflow API in Python to train features based on queue length and waiting time.
- Other tools utilized: SUMO, TraCl. Languages: Python, HTML/CSS

BIG DATA MANAGEMENT COURSE

@UC Riverside

(Sep 2019 – Dec 2019)

- HopScotch: Used GraphQL API in Python to query Yelp's dataset in real-time for LA pubs and Google OR tools for TSP solver.
- Utilized Google maps API to calculate distances between filtered pubs and generate markers on the map with JavaScript & HTML.
- Comparing efficiency of implementation between Hadoop & MapReduce in Java and Spark jobs in PySpark.

Educational Qualification:

MS, COMPUTER SCIENCE (DECEMBER 2020): University of California - Riverside

Courses: Big Data Management, Distributed Systems, Artificial Intelligence, Introduction to Deep Learning, Advanced Operating Systems, Database management Systems

BE, ELECTRONICS AND TELECOMMUNICATION (MAY 2015): D.Y. Patil College of Engineering., University of Pune